zemanta.com 2018-06-29

# Privacy - Zemanta

Effective as of May 25, 2018

**Introduction**

Protecting your privacy and right to choice is a top priority for Zemanta. Zemanta is a global provider of advertising technology to advertisers and agencies. This privacy policy explains Zemanta’s collection and use of data on websites where Zemanta’s proprietary Zemanta DSP technology is used to purchase ads (also known as “Zemanta One”). This privacy policy does not govern the collection and use of data on Zemanta’s corporate web site ([https://www.zemanta.com](https://www.zemanta.com/)). That data is governed by the section “Site Visitors”, found at <https://www.outbrain.com/legal/privacy#privacy-policy>, which is operated by Zemanta’s parent company, Outbrain Inc.

Zemanta is a member of IAB (Interactive Advertising Bureau) and adheres to its policies around online consumer privacy. While not a member, Zemanta adheres to Network Advertising Initiative Code of Conduct self-regulatory principles.

**Information We Collect Through Our Technology**

When you visit a website or application that uses the Zemanta One platform for targeted ads, we collect certain information about you and your device to help optimize ads and increase the likelihood that will be interested in an ad shown. Some of this information, including for example, your IP addresses and certain unique device identifiers, may identify a particular computer or device, and may be considered “personal data” in some jurisdictions in the European Union and elsewhere.

Information that we may collect includes: IP address, domain, browser type and language, referring website addresses, date/time of visits, page view data, search keywords, your activities and actions on publisher’s sites, browser history, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, geolocation (including city, country, zip code, and geographic coordinates, if you have enabled location services on your device), click data, types of advertisements viewed, and information about your device including device make, device model, device operating system, device operating system version, and data connection type. We do not collect any “sensitive personal data” as defined under European data protection laws.

We may also collect information about our partners’ interactions with you—for example, by placing pixels on an advertiser’s webpage so we can know if you ultimately purchased an item after viewing an advertisement bought through our platform or by integrating with the partners’ web analytics software, so we can know how long and where you engaged on their site. We may partner with other companies that are permitted to share anonymous information with us in order to enhance audience profiles. For example, we may partner with companies to learn the kinds of products you buy or express interest in.

**How we collect information**

We collect information in industry standard ways, including:

**Cookies** – Cookies are short strings of characters. Zemanta uses cookies to uniquely identify an internet browser and in turn a device. We sync those cookies with our partners, so we can identify users across environments and know which segments our partners identify them with. For more information about cookies, visit http://www.allaboutcookies.org/.

**Pixel Tags** – Pixel tags are transparent images or short snippets of Javascript that our partners and clients use to understand how their users interact with their properties online, including websites and mobile apps.

**Mobile Advertising Identifiers** – Mobile advertising IDs (like IDFA) are unique, non PII IDs associated with individual mobile devices. Users can reset them by instructing their device to do so.

**General Web Analytics** – We integrate with Web Analytics software of our clients and partners in order to observe how users behave after clicking on ads. We do not control how third party Web Analytics software collects the data as this is defined by its own privacy policy.

**How we use the information we collect**

We primarily use the information we collect to enable our partners and clients to buy appropriate advertising space across the Zemanta One platform, which allows buying advertisements on the web and in desktop and mobile apps.

This information is used to target ads to consumers on behalf of our advertisers. This means displaying ads that might be of interest to consumers sharing certain traits. In some cases, our data is used in conjunction with the information advertisers have collected themselves (for example by bringing their CRM data into Zemanta One platform). This information is also used to appropriately price the ads on behalf of our advertisers.

Zemanta and its third-party partners may disclose links to or the entirety of articles you read, and in connection therewith, you waive any rights you may have under the California Reader Privacy Protection Act, the United States Video Privacy Protection Act, and any similar federal, state, local, or foreign law. Third parties may be able to ascertain your identity by using information we disclose to them in anonymized form in conjunction with other information they may have.  
Data retention

Cookies that are used to identify browsers expire after one year or less on a user’s machine. Likewise, data Zemanta One platform retains about those identifiers is retained for 90 days. Log level data of served ads, such as IP address and date an ad is served may be retained indefinitely.

Zemanta also maintains a Data Retention Policy that details the retention period for personal data based on our analysis of how long the specific data is reasonably required for legal or business purposes. When we no longer need personal data, we securely delete or destroy it. Aggregated data, which cannot identify a device/browser (or individual) and is used for purposes of reporting and analysis, is maintained for as long as commercially necessary.

**Consumer Choice: Opt-Out**

Opt out means you inform Zemanta One platform that you wish Zemanta to delete the data it holds about your browser and cease collecting data while you remain opted-out (which means a non-unique opt-out cookie is set in your browser).

In practice, this means Zemanta One platform will not have and therefore will not be able to use any information specific to your browser to deliver targeted ads to you.

Please note that you will still see ads if you opt out, they just won’t be interest-based or otherwise targeted based on your browser’s cookie.

You can opt out on this page: <https://www.zemanta.com/opt-out>

Additionally, you can reset your Mobile Advertising Identifiers on your mobile device by following instructions for iOS devices and for Android Devices.

**Information Our Customers Collect**

Our customers and other third parties who use our technology may use their own tags, pixels, cookies, or other similar technology (or those of their other affiliates) within their advertisements and on certain websites. These customers maintain their own privacy policies and processes. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of customers that use our technology.

**Children**

None of our services are directed to children under 16. We do not knowingly collect personal data from anyone under 16 years of age. If we determine upon collection that you are under 16, we will not use or maintain your personal data. If we become aware that we have unknowingly collected personal data from a child under the age of 16, we will make reasonable efforts to delete such information from our records. If you’re a kid, please go play in the yard, don’t use or interact with Zemanta!

**European Territory Citizens**

In compliance with European privacy laws, in particular, the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), Zemanta provides specific additional rights for citizens of the European Territories such as the right to access, rectification, right to object, to complaint, erasure and blockage. More specifically:

  * The right to request information about whether and which personal data is processed by our company, and the right to demand that personal data is rectified or amended.
  * Under certain circumstances, the right to request that personal data should be deleted.
  * Under certain circumstances, the right to demand that the processing of personal data should be restricted.
  * Withdraw your consent to the processing and use of your data completely or partially at any time with future application.  
have the right to obtain your personal data in a common, structured and mechanically readable format.
  * Contact your data protection officer if there are any questions, comments, complaints or requests in connection with our statement on data protection and the processing of your personal data.
  * The right to complain to the responsible supervisory authority if believed that the processing of your personal data is in violation of the legislation.

In addition to the above, we reference certain rights for European Territory citizens throughout this Privacy Policy. Pursuant to the GDPR, citizens from “European Territories” mean the European Economic Area (EEA) and Switzerland. For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, the term “European Territories” shall continue to include the United Kingdom, even after the United Kingdom leaves the European Economic Area following Brexit.

**California Privacy Rights**

Under California Civil Code sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to ask us for a notice describing what categories of personal information we share with third parties or corporate affiliates for those third parties or corporate affiliates’ direct marketing purposes. That notice will identify the categories of information shared and will include a list of the third parties and affiliates with which it was shared, along with their names and addresses. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to info+privacy@zemanta.com or send to the following address: Zemanta Inc., 39 West 13th Street, 3rd floor, New York, NY 10011. Please allow 30 days for a response.

**“Do Not Track” Disclosure**

Some browsers transmit Do Not Track (DNT) signals to websites. Because there is no common understanding of how to interpret the DNT signal, Zemanta does not currently alter, change, or respond to DNT requests or signals from these browsers. We will continue to monitor industry activity in this area and reassess our DNT practices as necessary. In the meantime, you can use the range of other tools we provide to control data collection and use, including the ability to opt out in the Consumer Choice: Opt-Out section.

**Changes to this privacy policy**

Zemanta may update this privacy policy at any time (on a prospective basis). When we do, we will post an updated version here, and indicate the date of revision at the top of this page. We may, but are not required to, give you notice through other means. We encourage you to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the information we collect.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact us at:

Zemanta Inc. 39 West 13th Street 3rd floor, 10011 New York, NY

If we do not satisfactorily answer your questions or concerns, you may also contact the following for advice, support or complaints:

  * Our external Data Protection Officer (“DPO”): ePrivacy GmbH, represented by Prof. Dr. Christoph Bauer. ePrivacy GmbH can be reached directly at privacy@eprivacy.eu; and/or
  * The Information Commissioner’s Officer, which is our lead supervisory service within the European Territories.
